HAN MENG LOO

loohanmeng@gmail.com +44 7397870392

PROFILE

 A software engineer with 2 years of practical experience in software development by applying technical knowledge throughout the software development lifecycle, working in a collaborative environment to deliver quality software solutions that address and solve business problems. I am proficient in multiple platforms and languages, keen to continue developing my skills and experiences with the latest development tools and methodologies.

EMPLOYMENT

Software Engineer FanDuel Jan 2022 - Present

Organic Growth, Growth Products Domain

- Codify infrastructure using Terraform to ensure a reusable, reproduceable deployment process on AWS.
- Contributed to internal frontend React library to allow for consistent UI across FanDuel pages.
- Developed microservices and internal APIs using Java Spring for the National Football League.

Junior Software Developer

Wildcat Applications Ltd

June 2021 - Jan 2022

Cenefits, Community Benefits Realisation Tool

- Introduced a mass assignment feature to allow admins to assign/unassign executives en masse.
- Improved productivity of admins and project managers by allowing them to create private notes with visibility settings.
- Adopted test-driven development to implement requested features by the Glasgow City Council and City of Edinburgh Council.

Graduate Teaching Assistant

University of Glasgow

Sep 2020 – March 2021

Provided support and resolved student queries to complete weekly lab exercises for the Functional Programming, Programming Systems Development and Database Systems course.

Software Developer, Intern/ Part time

Wildcat Applications Ltd

May - Nov 2020

Cenefits, Community Benefits Realisation Tool

- Improved dashboard displays to include contract summary highlighting contracts with higher priority.
- Introduced a new view for organisation admins to edit and manage benefits easily.
- Implemented search filters to allow users to view benefits that matches the search criteria.
- Provided technical support during client onboarding.

Software Developer, Intern

Fresh Futures Malaysia

University of Glasgow

June - Sep 2019

Seeka, Global Course Finder

- Contributed to the growth of the app's database by improving upon the existing data fetching process
- Reduced data entry cost through automation.

EDUCATION Glasgow

Year 2016 - 2021

- MSci in Software Engineering with Honours of the first class.
- Fast CPU-based software retina, Master's Thesis A biologically inspired software retina system that compress visual inputs to reduce memory requirements in areas such as robotics and deep learning.
- Robotics Web App, Bachelor's Thesis The Robotics Web App has been built to remove any need for students to install and set up an environment before working on the lab exercises.